[Music]
all right welcome to day four everybody
Why Don't We Begin by quickly going over
the homework from day three so you may
remember I asked you to extract one of
these navigation links into its own
dedicated component so let's do that now
together so in my components directory
and actually a quick note uh I made it
capital here it's kind of muscle memory
from other Frameworks I also use uh but
it can absolutely be lowercase if you
prefer all right anyways uh nav link.
blade. PHP all right let's grab this and
paste it in like so switch back and now
this can become xnav link like so all
right obviously a little more work to do
but let's have a look in the browser all
right come back give it a refresh and
yeah we do see the home link but it's
not very functional right this needs to
be dynamic so that it can be used for
any nav link item all right so why don't
we do that slot technique here let's
come back to layouts and now this can
become
home this one can become about and this
one can become contact all right come
back give it a refresh all right that
looks good but now of course you'll
notice they're all linking to the exact
same place all right so this is where
the homework got a little bit tricky you
may not know about this so it sounds
like I need to pass in a an href like we
did like we do with a normal link right
that would make
sense however in the nav link component
how do we access it right uh well as it
turns out all layal blade components
have access to an attributes object and
that object will contain uh all the
details for any attributes you pass and
by attributes I mean hre I mean ID I
mean class any of these okay so if I
come back to our component yeah what we
could do initially is just open up an
echo um PHP Echo and then say attributes
and that will properly be stringified
now yeah again keep in mind attributes
is an object so there's actually more
bells and whistles than what you
initially see here for example if you
want to merge in some sensible defaults
you could do so like this but we're
getting a little ahead of ourselves so
let's keep it very simple right now all
right back to the browser give it a
refresh and now we should see the about
page page and the contact page and yeah
just to be crystal clear here what if I
wanted to say uh the about page should
have a style tag where the color is
green or something like that well that
too will be included in that attributes
object so if I come back and give it a
refresh sure enough it's green okay so
now you're probably thinking okay fine
but why would we ever do this uh and the
answer is well maybe for simple things
you wouldn't however in real life a
navlink is a little bit more complicated
than a simple anchor tag uh think about
it you will need specific classes or
styling based on whether it is the
currently active page or not um there
might be other situations where the
presentation should differ based upon I
don't know where you are in the website
or what your screen size is anyways the
whole point is it gets a little bit more
complicated than a basic anchor tag in
most cases so if we extract all of this
into its own naving component
we can isolate any of that complexity
into a single file which is really cool
all right but yeah that was just an
example I'm going to delete it and now I
want to make things look a little bit
more attractive so here's what I'm going
to do I'm going to switch over to
tailwind
css.com and actually on that note before
we begin um if you don't know what tail1
CSS is trust me it's entirely fine you
don't need to it's not a prerequisite
for the course it's just a way to
quickly and rapidly build up um some
layouts and such without having to refer
to a CSS file so Tailwind is a CSS